<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
<!-- +++ Economy Civics Option +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Barter -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BARTER</Tag>
		<English>Barter</English>
		<French>Troc</French>
		<German>Tauschhandel</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BARTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Barter is a type of trade in which goods or services are directly exchanged for other goods and/or services, without the use of money. It can be bilateral or multilateral, and usually exists parallel to monetary systems in most developed countries, though to a very limited extent. Barter usually replaces money as the method of exchange in times of monetary crisis, when the currency is unstable and devalued by hyperinflation. [PARAGRAPH:2]In the past, goods were to be exchanged in the goods of another without considering of its money value. To organize production and to distribute goods and services among their populations, many pre-capitalist or pre-market economies relied on tradition, top-down command, or community democracy instead of market exchange organised using barter. Relations of reciprocity and/or redistribution substituted for market exchange. Trade and barter were primarily reserved for trade between communities or countries. It is also used when the monetary system failed to measure the economic value of goods.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BARTER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases food and production from trade routes by 35% but also decreases gold 50% from trade routes. Increases gold income by 25% in capital and decreases culture by 10% in all cities. Bazaar, Market and Grocer can be built at reduced cost. Corporations have no effect.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Coinage -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_COINAGE</Tag>
		<English>Coinage</English>
		<French>Système monétaire</French>
		<German>M&#252;nzwesen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_COINAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The first metal coins are regarded by some as having been invented in China. The earliest known Chinese metal tokens were made ca. 900 BC, discovered in a tomb near Anyang. These were replicas in bronze of earlier Chinese money, cowrie shells, so they were named Bronze Shell. Most numismatists, however, regard these as well as later Chinese bronzes that were replicas of knives, spades, and hoes as money but not as coins because they didn't at least initially carry a mark or marks certifying them to be of a definite exchange value.[NEWLINE]Coins originated independently in Anatolia, with most numismatists regarding Lydia as the birthplace of coinage. The Greeks soon adopted the Lydian practice and extended it to commerce and trade, with coinage following Greek colonization and influence first around the eastern Mediterranean and soon after to North Africa (including Egypt), Syria, Persia, and the Balkans.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_COINAGE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Guilds -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_GUILDS</Tag>
		<English>Guilds</English>
		<French>Guildes</French>
		<German>Gilden</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_GUILDS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Mercantile -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MERCANTILE</Tag>
		<English>Mercantile</English>
		<French>Mercantile</French>
		<German>Merkantil</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MERCANTILE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Mercantile represents an economy using the mercantile system. The mercantile system believes that the volume of the world economy is constant and the prosperity of a nation is equivalent to the amount capital owned by that country. Capital is represented by gold and silver bullion owned by the government, and the government actively attempts to make the exports higher than imports in order to create a net gain of capital. The government does this by increasing tariffs, or taxes on imports. Civilizations not using the mercantile system tend to choose not to trade with mercantilist nations due to the high tariffs, so trade is restricted to domestic trade and foreign trade with other mercantilist nations where the tariffs balance out. Some scholars consider it to be an early form of capitalism while others consider it to be an entirely different economic theory.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MERCANTILE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Free Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_LAISSEZ_FAIRE</Tag>
		<English>Free Market</English>
		<French>Libre Marché</French>
		<German>Freier Markt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_LAISSEZ_FAIRE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Laissez-Faire is a French term meaning "let do." Laissez-Faire represents many types of capitalism, including the Chicago School, the Austrian School, monetarism, and supply-side economics, all of which believe the government should not intervene in the economy through regulations. Until the formation of the Federal Reserve System, laissez-faire economists were against the idea of a Central Bank. Due to lack of regulations, workers prefer having higher wages than better working environments, thus decreasing their health. Time periods using laissez-faire economics are characterized as having a massive boost in production and increased foreign and domestic trade.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_LAISSEZ_FAIRE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Planned -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PLANNED</Tag>
		<English>Planned</English>
		<French>Planifié</French>
		<German>Planwirtschaft</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PLANNED_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Planned represents an economy completely controlled, owned and planned by the government, otherwise known as state capitalism. Under a planned economy, all labor, capital, production, agriculture, utilities, and finances are run by the government, and all service businesses are owned by the government. Because there are no private companies, no trade exists. Planned economies are able to concentrate their resources on major projects such as world wonders and world projects, but are very costly to maintain.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PLANNED_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Corporatist -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CORPORATIST</Tag>
		<English>Corporatist</English>
		<French>Corporatiste</French>
		<German>Korporativ</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CORPORATIST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Corporatist represents an economic policy that is geared toward giving the highest possible profits and highest possible growth to domestic corporations at the expense of consumers and workers. Corporatism can be caused either by corporate executives running the government or from bribes by corporate lobbyists. Corporatism leads to a large amount of wealth accumulated by the government and a much lower cost of maintaining corporations, but it severely angers the bulk of society: the working class, so it should only be used if you are sure you can satisfy the people with buildings and resources. As of now, no country has employed a corporatist economy.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CORPORATIST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Regulated -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_KEYNESIAN</Tag>
		<English>Regulated</English>
		<French>Régulé</French>
		<German>Reguliert</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_KEYNESIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Regulated represents the form of capitalism as advocated by economist John Maynard Keynes. Keynes advocated a mixed economy where the government intervenes in the economy in order to increase demand and stimulate the economy. The expensive regulations and bureaucracy used to maintain the interventionist policies come from taxation with a bulk of the taxes coming from corporations. Keynesian economists believe in smoothing the business cycle, which causes booms and busts, by raising taxes and interest rates to cool the economy and lowering taxes and interest rates to stimulate it. The result is a relatively stable economy void of depressions and panics, but also of giant boom periods. Keynesians also believe the government should actively invest in infrastructure as a method of increasing demand.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_KEYNESIAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Green -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_GREEN</Tag>
		<English>Green</English>
		<French>Vert</French>
		<German>Gr&#252;n</German>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Future Civics Options +++ -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_FUTURE</Tag>
		<English>Future</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_ABBR_FUTURE</Tag>
		<English>Fut.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Nothing -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_NOTHING</Tag>
		<English>None</English>
		<French>Aucun</French>
		<German>Keine</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_NOTHING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English></English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_NOTHING_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English></English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Paradise -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PARADISE</Tag>
		<English>Paradise</English>
		<French>Paradis</French>
		<German>Paradies</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PARADISE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Ecotopias are governments which focus a return to nature while maintaining technology.  The use of high technologies is used to reduce pollution while maintain a high standard of living.  Ecotopias are vulnerable to war, considering it being the greatest threat to the environment.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PARADISE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Post Scarcity -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_POST_SCARCITY</Tag>
		<English>Post-Scarcity</English>
		<French>Après-Pénurie</French>
		<German>Post-Mangelwirtschaft</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_POST_SCARCITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>With robots producing goods around the clock, the need for all but the most skilled labor became obsolete for mass production.  Without the need for labor, people had to figure out what to do with all the time, and cheap goods.  This led to an age of great excess and decadence, as well as various health effects which accompany such indulgence.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_POST_SCARCITY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Superhuman -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUPERHUMAN</Tag>
		<English>Superhuman</English>
		<French>Superhumain</French>
		<German>&#220;bermenschlich</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUPERHUMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The use of technologies to genetically engineered supermen, who are immune to disease, have perfect metabolisms, and have other qualities which would never arise naturally in humanity.  Those born outside of genetic engineering serve as an underclass, which does tasks below the class of supermen, but are still too expensive to take care of throw robotics.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUPERHUMAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUPERHUMAN_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]-50%% Clones, Automatons, Genetic Soldier and Super Soldier costs</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Coût de production de -50%% pour : Clones, Automates, Soldats Génétiques and Super-Soldats.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]-50%% Kosten f&#252;r Klone, Automatons, Gensoldaten and Supersoldaten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Supremacy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUPREMACY</Tag>
		<English>Supremacy</English>
		<French>Suprématie</French>
		<German>Vormacht</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUPREMACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>World domination in the past was largely a dream due to the rebellious nature of protectorates and limits on populations which can be put under direct rule combined with the slow flow of communication.  With the rise of instantaneous communication, policies can be changed and troops can be moved with such precision and timing which solves the problems of ages past.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUPREMACY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Technocracy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TECHNOCRACY</Tag>
		<English>Technocracy</English>
		<French>Technocratie</French>
		<German>Technokratie</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TECHNOCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Technocracy is a form of government in which engineers, scientists, and other technical experts are in control of decision making in their respective fields. Technocracy is a governmental or organizational system where decision makers are selected based upon how highly knowledgeable they are, rather than how much political capital they hold. Technocrats are individuals with technical training and occupations who perceive many important societal problems as being solvable, often while proposing technology-focused solutions.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TECHNOCRACY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TECHNOCRACY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]New Units Receive [LINK=PROMOTION_SENSORS]Sensors I[\LINK] Promotion (with Smart Dust tech)</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Les Nouvelles Unités sont dotées de [LINK=PROMOTION_SENSORS]Sensors I[\LINK] (avec la Technologie [LINK=SMART_DUST]Déchets Intelligents[\LINK])</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Neue Einheiten erhalten die [LINK=PROMOTION_SENSORS]Sensoren I[\LINK]-Beförderung (mit der Technologie "Intelligenter Staub")</German>
	</TEXT>
	
<!-- +++ Government Civics Option +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Might -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MIGHT</Tag>
		<English>Might</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MIGHT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>There is no formal government structure, but typically there will be one person whom others defer to.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MIGHT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>There is no benefit to this structure and as there is no real ocncept of culture.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Chiefdom -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHIEFDOM</Tag>
		<English>Chiefdom</English>
		<French>Chef de Tribu</French>
		<German>Stammessystem</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHIEFDOM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A chiefdom is a type of complex society of varying degrees of centralization that is led by an individual known as a chief. [PARAGRAPH:2]In anthropological theory, one model of human social development rooted in ideas of cultural evolution describes a chiefdom as a form of social organization more complex than a tribe or a band society, and less complex than a state or a civilization. The most succinct definition of a chiefdom in anthropology belongs to Robert L. Carneiro: "An autonomous political unit comprising a number of villages or communities under the permanent control of a paramount chief" (Carneiro 1981: 45).[PARAGRAPH:2]Chiefdoms are characterized by pervasive inequality and centralization of authority. At least two inherited social classes (elite and commoner) are present (Ancient Hawaiian chiefdoms had as many as four social classes), although an individual might change social class during a lifetime by extraordinary behavior. A single lineage/family of the elite class becomes the ruling elite of the chiefdom, with the greatest influence, power, and prestige. Kinship is typically an organizing principle, while marriage, age, and gender can affect one's social status and role.[PARAGRAPH:2]A single simple chiefdom is generally composed of a central community surrounded by or near a number of smaller subsidiary communities. All of these communities recognize the authority of a single kin group or individual with hereditary centralized power, dwelling in the primary community. Each community will have its own leaders, which are usually in a tributary and/or subservient relationship with the ruling elite of the primary community.</English>
		<French>Un domaine de chefs de tribus est un type de société complexe avec différents degrés de centratlisation, mené par un leader : le chef de tribut. [PARAGRAPH:2]Dans les théories  anthropologiques, un modèle du développement social des êtreshumains a pris racine dans les idées de l'évolution culturelle écrit un domaine de chefs comme un forme d'organisation sociale plus complexe qu'une tribu ou une bande, et moins complexe qu'un état ou une civilization. La définition la plus succinte en antropologie est celle de Robert L. Carneiro: "Une entité polotiquement autonome comprenant un nombre de villages ou des communautés sous le contrôle permanant d'un Chef" (Carneiro 1981: 45).[PARAGRAPH:2]Les domaines de chefs sont caractérisés par une grande inégalité et la centralisation de l'autorité. Un moins deux classes sociales y sont associées (l'élite et la base - les ancients domaines Hawaiiens avait au moins quatre classes sociales), et un individu pouvait changer de classe sociale au cours de sa vie en accomplissant un exploit par exemple. Une seule lignée/famille de la classe d'élite devient dirigeantedu domaine,avec la plus grande influence, le pouvoir et le prestige.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHIEFDOM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Units gain more experience inside cultural borders and Great Generals are more likely to appear and war weariness grows slower. Food production in capital is increased by 10%. Larger empire suffers from increased maintenance costs.</English>
		<French>Les Unités gagnent plus d'expérience à l'intérieur du territoire. Probabilité plus importante de Généraux Illustres. Mécontentement dû à la Guerre évolue lentement. La production de Nourriture de la Capitale augment de 10%. Les Grands Empires souffrent des coûts de maintenance élevés.</French>
		<German>Einheiten sammeln innerhalb der kulturellen Grenzen mehr Erfahrung und die Wahrscheinlichkeit des Erscheinens von Gro&#223;en Gener&#228;len ist erh&#246;ht, die Kriegsm&#252;digkeit w&#228;chst langsamer. Nahrungsmittelproduktion in der Hauptstadt ist um 10% erh&#246;ht. Gr&#246;&#223;ere Imperien leiden unter erh&#246;hten Unterhaltskosten.</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Despotism -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DESPOTISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Despotism is a form of government characterized by a ruler who wields absolute power over his people. Despite the word's negative connotations, a leader doesn't necessarily have to be a corrupt, evil megalomaniac to be a despot; it is possible to be a benevolent despot, though history records few cases of such. [PARAGRAPH:2]The strength of this form of government is that the ruler can easily implement his decisions; he does not need to compromise, cajole, or bribe anyone to get the job done. The weakness of this form of government is that the ruler can implement bad decisions just as easily as good ones; with no checks and balances, how can he be stopped? Also, there is a lot of truth in the old saying, "Power corrupts; absolute power corrupts absolutely." And though as said before, despots don't need to be corrupt, evil megalomaniacs, many of them end up that way.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le despotisme est une forme de gouvernement au sein duquel le dirigeant d&#233;tient le pouvoir absolu sur son peuple. Contrairement &#224; ce que l'on pense, un despote n'est pas forc&#233;ment un m&#233;galomane corrompu et mauvais. Le monde a connu des despotes bienveillants, m&#234;me s'il y en a eu peu. [PARAGRAPH:2]La force de ce type de gouvernement r&#233;side dans le fait que le dirigeant peut imposer facilement ses d&#233;cisions, sans passer par des compromis, des cajoleries ou des pots de vins. La faiblesse de ces r&#233;gimes r&#233;side dans le fait que le dirigeant peut aussi facilement imposer ses mauvaises d&#233;cisions puisqu'il n'y a pas de contre-pouvoirs. De plus, il y a une certaine v&#233;rit&#233; dans l'expression : "le pouvoir corrompt, le pouvoir absolu corrompt absolument." Et m&#234;me si les despotes ne sont pas n&#233;cessairement corrompus, beaucoup d'entre eux finissent par le devenir t&#244;t ou tard.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Despotismus ist eine Willk&#252;rherrschaft, bei der ein Herrscher absolute Macht &#252;ber sein Volk aus&#252;bt. Trotz der eher negativen Belegung des Wortes ist dieser Herrscher allerdings nicht zwingend korrupt, b&#246;se und gr&#246;&#223;enwahnsinnig. Es hat im Laufe der Menschheitsgeschichte durchaus (wenn auch nur wenige) g&#252;tige Despoten gegeben. [PARAGRAPH:2]Der Vorteil dieser Regierungsform ist die einfache Umsetzbarkeit der Vorstellungen des Herrschers. Dieser muss keine Kompromisse eingehen und mit niemandem verhandeln, um seinen Willen durchzusetzen. Allerdings gilt dies f&#252;r segensreiche UND schlechte Entscheidungen, da diese von keiner gleichberechtigten oder &#252;bergeordneten Instanz in Frage gestellt werden. Daher ist das alte Sprichwort: "Macht korrumpiert, absolute Macht korrumpiert absolut" leider in aller Regel zutreffend. Fr&#252;her oder sp&#228;ter verliert auch der g&#252;tigste Despot seinen Sinn f&#252;r die Realit&#228;t.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il dispotismo &#232; una forma di governo nella quale un sovrano esercita un potere assoluto sul proprio popolo. Malgrado le connotazioni negative della parola, un despota non deve essere necessariamente corrotto o agire da pazzo megalomane; sono esistiti anche despoti benevoli, malgrado nel corso della storia non se ne siano visti molti. [PARAGRAPH:2]La forza di questa forma di governo &#232; che il sovrano pu&#242; mettere in pratica facilmente le proprie decisioni: non ha bisogno di corrompere, lusingare o scendere a compromessi con nessuno. La debolezza di questo tipo di governo, invece, &#232; che il sovrano pu&#242; rischiare di agire in modo errato quanto giusto e senza contrappesi, chi &#232; in grado di fermarlo? Inoltre, c'&#232; del vero nel vecchio detto "il potere corrompe; il potere assoluto ti corrompe assolutamente". E, come detto in precedenza, sebbene un sovrano non debba per forza essere malvagio o megalomane, molti sono finiti cos&#236;.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El despotismo es una forma de gobierno caracterizada por la presencia de un gobernante que ejerce un poder absoluto sobre su pueblo. A pesar de las connotaciones negativas de la palabra, el l&#237;der no tiene por qu&#233; ser necesariamente un megal&#243;mano corrupto y malvado. Es posible ser un d&#233;spota benevolente, aunque la historia no ha registrado demasiados casos. [PARAGRAPH:2]La principal ventaja de esta forma de gobierno radica en que el gobernante puede poner en pr&#225;ctica sus decisiones con facilidad. No necesita convencer, seducir o sobornar a nadie para conseguirlo. Su debilidad estriba en que las malas decisiones son igualmente f&#225;ciles de impulsar. Sin equilibrios ni contrapoderes, nadie puede detener al d&#233;spota. Adem&#225;s, hay mucha verdad en el antiguo dicho que asegura, "el poder corrompe, y el poder absoluto corrompe absolutamente". Y, aunque tal como se ha dicho antes, los d&#233;spotas no tienen por qu&#233; ser megal&#243;manos corruptos y malvados, muchos de ellos acaban si&#233;ndolo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DESPOTISM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The most primitive Government civic. Decreased war anger; +2 unhealth in all cities, less happiness in largest cities; Faster military unit production</English>
		<French>Doctrine de Gouvernment la plus primitive. Réduit le mécontentement lié à la Guerre; +2 malades dans toutes les Villes, moins de bonheur dans les grandes Villes; Production des unités militaires plus rapide.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Monarchy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_HEREDITARY_RULE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Hereditary Rule is a form of government wherein the rulership is passed down from one member of the family to the next. This kind of succession is most often associated with monarchical rulers, but it occasionally appears in despotisms or even purportedly communist regimes - North Korea, for example. There is often a religious justification for hereditary rule; kings are said to rule by "divine right" or "the mandate of Heaven." [PARAGRAPH:2]The strength of hereditary rule is that there is usually a clear line of succession, and thus perhaps less squabbling for power when the current monarch dies. (There are plenty of exceptions to this rule throughout history, of course.) Further, there may be a certain amount of familial pressure on the ruler to not mess things up too badly for the next generation. However, hereditary rule suffers the same kind of weaknesses as do all unelected rulers; the leader is not answerable to the people, and it can be extremely difficult to get rid of a bad one.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le droit h&#233;r&#233;ditaire est une forme de gouvernement par lequel le pouvoir est transmis d'un membre de la famille r&#233;gnante &#224; un autre. Ce genre de successions est souvent associ&#233; &#224; la monarchie, mais elles sont aussi parfois appliqu&#233;es dans les r&#233;gimes despotiques, voire dans les soi-disant r&#233;gimes communistes, comme la Cor&#233;e du Nord, par exemple. Le droit h&#233;r&#233;ditaire est souvent justifi&#233; par la religion. Les rois sont ainsi de "droit divin" ou "mandat&#233; par le ciel". [PARAGRAPH:2]La force du droit h&#233;r&#233;ditaire r&#233;side dans une relative tranquillit&#233; lors des successions, l'h&#233;ritier &#233;tant connu d'avance. L'histoire, cependant, est riche d'exceptions &#224; cette r&#232;gle. De plus, la personne r&#233;gnante est plus ou moins surveill&#233;e par sa famille, qui ne tient pas &#224; ce qu'il laisse &#224; ses successeurs une situation chaotique. Cependant, le droit h&#233;r&#233;ditaire souffre des faiblesses propres aux r&#233;gimes dans lesquels le dirigeant n'est pas &#233;lu. Le dirigeant n'a pas &#224; r&#233;pondre devant le peuple, et aussi mauvais qu'il puisse &#234;tre, il est tr&#232;s difficile de s'en d&#233;barrasser.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Das Erbrecht ist eine Regierungsform, bei der die Regentschaft von einem Familienmitglied an das n&#228;chste weitergegeben wird. Diese Art der Nachfolge wird h&#228;ufig in Monarchien praktiziert. Gelegentlich wird aber auch im Despotismus oder Kommunismus (Nordkorea) darauf zur&#252;ckgegriffen. Das Erbrecht st&#252;tzt sich nicht selten auf eine religi&#246;se Rechtfertigung in Form eines "Gottesgnadentums" des Monarchen. [PARAGRAPH:2]Der Vorteil des Erbrechts ist die im Regelfall klar geregelte Erbfolge. Dadurch halten sich Streitigkeiten nach dem Tod des Monarchen meist in Grenzen. Dar&#252;ber hinaus kann die Familie betr&#228;chtlichen Druck auf den Herrscher aus&#252;ben. Allerdings ist ein nach dem Erbrecht eingesetzter Herrscher seinem Volk keinerlei Rechenschaft schuldig und es ist relativ schwierig, einen ungeliebten Regenten abzusetzen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Quello ereditario &#232; una forma di governo nel quale il potere del sovrano passa da un membro della famiglia a un altro. Questo tipo di successione viene spesso attribuito ai sovrani monarchici, ma si &#232; verificato anche in despotismi e regimi comunisti, dei quali la Corea del Nord ne &#232; un esempio. C'&#232; sempre una giustificazione religiosa dietro un governo ereditario: si dice che i re goverino per "diritto divino" o per "mandato del Cielo". [PARAGRAPH:2]La forza di un governo ereditario &#232; che spesso la successione &#232; ben delineata e, alla morte del sovrano, i litigi sono ridotti al minimo. (Naturalmente, esistono molte eccezioni alla regola nel corso della storia). Inoltre, c'&#232; molta pressione sul sovrano da parte della famiglia per non rovinare il futuro delle generazioni successive. Tuttavia, il governo ereditario soffre dello stesso problema di altre situazioni: il sovrano non viene eletto dal popolo ed &#232; estremamente difficile disfarsi di uno particolarmente incapace.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El gobierno hereditario es una forma de gobierno en la que la autoridad se transmite de un miembro a otro de la familia. Esta clase de sucesi&#243;n suele asociarse a gobernantes mon&#225;rquicos, pero en ocasiones aparece tambi&#233;n en despotados o en reg&#237;menes te&#243;ricamente comunistas, como por ejemplo Corea del Norte. En el gobierno hereditario casi siempre existe una justificaci&#243;n religiosa. Se dice que los reyes gobiernan por "derecho divino" o por "mandato del cielo". [PARAGRAPH:2]La solidez del gobierno hereditario radica en que suele existir una l&#237;nea clara de sucesi&#243;n, lo que tiende a limitar las luchas de poder a la muerte del monarca (naturalmente, la historia est&#225; llena de excepciones a esta regla). Adem&#225;s, el gobernante suele enfrentarse a una cierta dosis de presi&#243;n familiar que le obliga a cuidar su legado para la generaci&#243;n siguiente. Sin embargo, los gobernantes hereditarios adolecen de las mismas debilidades que todos los l&#237;deres no electos; no son responsables ante el pueblo y, cuando son malos, puede ser extremadamente complicado librarse de ellos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_HEREDITARY_RULE</Tag>
		<English>Monarchy</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_HEREDITARY_RULE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>You may assign unlimited noble specialists in your cities; Military units in cities increase happiness; +1 unhealth in all cities; Faster military unit production; +15% food, +10% hammers, -10% commerce, -10% science in all cities. +1 hammer from Fortress. +1 Support cost per military unit</English>
		<French>Pas de limite pour les spécialistes Noble dans toutes les Villes; Les unités Militaires augmente le Bonheur; +1 malade dans toutes les Villes; Production des unités militaires plus rapide; +15% nourriture, +10% production, -10% commerce, -10% science dans toutes les Villes. +1 production de Forteresse. +1 de coût d'entretien par unité militaire.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Republic -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_REPUBLIC</Tag>
		<English>Republic</English>
		<French>République</French>
		<German>Republik</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_REPUBLIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A republic is a form of government in which the citizens choose their leaders and the people (or at least a part of its people) have an impact on its government. The word "republic" is derived from the Latin phrase res publica, which can be translated as "a public affair". [PARAGRAPH:2]Both modern and ancient republics vary widely in their ideology and composition. The most common definition of a republic is a state without a monarch. In republics such as the United States and France the executive is legitimated both by a constitution and by popular suffrage. In the United States, James Madison defined republic in terms of representative democracy as opposed to direct democracy , and this usage is still employed by many viewing themselves as "republicans". In modern political science, republicanism refers to a specific ideology that is based on civic virtue and is considered distinct from ideologies such as liberalism. [PARAGRAPH:2]Most often a republic is a sovereign country, but there are also subnational entities that are referred to as republics, or which have governments that are described as "republican" in nature. For instance, Article IV of the Constitution of the United States "guarantee[s] to every State in this Union a Republican form of Government." The Soviet Union was a single nation composed of distinct and legally sovereign Soviet Socialist Republics.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_REPUBLIC_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Federal -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FEDERAL</Tag>
		<English>Federal</English>
		<French>Fédéral</French>
		<German>F&#246;deral</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FEDERAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Federal represents government form where nation or empire consists of several states which all have rights to create their own laws as long as those laws follow the guidelines set by the federal government. Each state is ruled by localized government and representatives are elected every 4-6 years. Two good examples of federal systems today are The United States and European Union.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FEDERAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Democracy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DEMOCRACY</Tag>
		<English>Democracy</English>
		<French>Démocratie</French>
		<German>Demokratie</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DEMOCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Democracy is a political government either carried out directly by the people (direct democracy) or by means of elected representatives of the people (Representative democracy). Even though there is no specific, universally accepted definition of 'democracy', there are two principles that any definition of democracy includes, equality and freedom. These principles are reflected by all citizens being equal before the law, and having equal access to power, and freedom is secured by legitimized rights and liberties, which are generally protected by a constitution. [PARAGRAPH:2]There are several varieties of democracy, some of which provide better representation and more freedoms for their citizens than others. However, if any democracy is not carefully legislated to avoid an uneven distribution of political power with balances, such as the separation of powers, then a branch of the system of rule could accumulate power and become harmful to the democracy itself.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DEMOCRACY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Fascism -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FASCIST</Tag>
		<English>Fascism</English>
		<French>Fasciste</French>
		<German>Faschismus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FASCIST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Fascists seek to organize a nation on corporatist perspectives; values; and systems such as the political system and the economy. Scholars generally consider fascism to be on the far right of the conventional left-right political spectrum, although some scholars claim that fascism has been influenced by both the left and the right. [PARAGRAPH:2]Fascists believe that a nation is an organic community that requires strong leadership, collective identity, and the will and ability to commit violence and wage war in order to keep the nation strong. Fascists identify violence and war as actions that create national regeneration, spirit and vitality. Fascists claim that culture is created by collective national society and its state, that cultural ideas are what give individuals identity, and thus rejects individualism. In viewing the nation as an integrated collective community, fascists claim that pluralism is a dysfunctional aspect of society, and justify a totalitarian state as a means to represent the nation in its entirety. Fascism rejects and resists autonomy of cultural or ethnic groups who are not considered part of the fascists' nation and who refuse to assimilate or are unable to be assimilated. Fascists consider attempts to create such autonomy as an affront and threat to the nation.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FASCIST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	
<!-- +++ Power Civics Option +++ -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_POWER</Tag>
		<English>Power</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_ABBR_POWER</Tag>
		<English>Pow.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Junta -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_OLIGARCHY</Tag>
		<English>Junta</English>
		<French>Junte</French>
		<German>Junta</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_OLIGARCHY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Junta or military junta represents a civic where few individuals who have gained their power by using any means necessary rule the nation. They are often militaristic leaders or tribal chiefs. Most of the ancient world civilizations where oligarchies and there are few still even today, like for example North Korea and Burma. Oligarchy was the starting push for nobility (aristocracy) when those leaders passed on their status to their children.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_OLIGARCHY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Nobility -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ARISTOCRACY</Tag>
		<English>Nobility</English>
		<French>Noblesse</French>
		<German>Adelsherrschaft</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ARISTOCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Nobility is a state-privileged status which is generally hereditary. Titles of nobility are usually associated with present or former monarchies. The term originally referred to those who were "known" or "notable" and was applied to the highest social class in pre-modern societies. In the feudal system (in Europe and elsewhere), the nobility were generally those who held a fief, often land or office, under vassalage, i.e., in exchange for allegiance and various, mainly military, services to the Monarch and at lower levels to another nobleman. It rapidly came to be seen as a hereditary caste, sometimes associated with a right to bear a hereditary title and, for example in pre-revolutionary France, enjoying fiscal and other privileges. While noble status formerly conferred significant privileges, today, in most Western countries, noble status is a purely honorary dignity. In the United Kingdom, where some peerage titles, until recently, guaranteed a seat in the Upper House of the Parliament, there are still some residual privileges. [PARAGRAPH:2]Nobility is a historical, social and often legal notion, distinct from socio-economic status which is mainly based on income and possessions. Being wealthy or influential does not automatically make one a noble, nor are all nobles wealthy and influential (aristocratic families have lost their fortunes in various ways, and the concept of the 'poor nobleman' is almost as old as nobility itself). Countries without a feudal tradition do not have a nobility as such. [PARAGRAPH:2]European nobility originated from the feudal/seignorial system that arose in Europe during the Middle Ages. Originally, knights or nobles were mounted warriors who swore allegiance to their sovereign and promised to fight for him in exchange for an allocation of land (usually together with serfs living there). During the time period known as the Military Revolution, nobles gradually lost their role of raising and commanding private armies, as many nations created cohesive national armies. This was coupled with a loss of the social-economic power of the nobility, owing to the economic changes of the Renaissance and the growing economic importance of the merchant classes (or bourgeoisie), which increased still further during the Industrial Revolution. In countries where the nobility was the dominant class, the bourgeoisie gradually grew in power; a rich city merchant was more influential than a minor rural nobleman. However, in many countries at this time, the nobility retained great social and political importance; for instance, the UK's government was dominated by the nobility until the middle of the 19th century and thereafter the powers of the nobility were progressively reduced by legislation (see Reform of the House of Lords).</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ARISTOCRACY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Patrician -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PATRICIAN</Tag>
		<English>Patrician</English>
		<French>Patriciens</French>
		<German>Patrizier</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PATRICIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The term patrician originally referred to a group of elite citizens in ancient Rome, including both their natural and adopted members. In the late Roman Empire, the class was broadened to include high council officials, and after the fall of the Western Empire it remained a high honorary title in the Byzantine Empire. Medieval patrician classes were once again formally defined groups of elite burgher families in many medieval Italian republics, such as Venice and Genoa, and subsequently "patrician" became a vaguer term used for aristocrats and elite bourgeoisie in many countries. [PARAGRAPH:2]Patricians were bestowed special status as Roman citizens. They were better represented in the Roman assemblies. The Comitia Centuriata, the main legislative body, was divided into 193 voting centuriae (centuries). The first two classes (which consisted largely of patricians) together had 98 centuriae, a number which was enough to obtain a majority, despite the fact that they were fewer in number. That meant that if the patricians acted in concord, they could always determine the result of the voting of the people's assembly. So, although it was not forbidden for plebeians to hold magistracies, the patricians dominated the political scene for centuries. [PARAGRAPH:2]In the beginning of the Republic, all priesthoods were closed to non-patricians. There was a belief that patricians communicated better with the Roman gods, so they alone could perform the sacred rites and take the auspices. This view had political consequences, since in the beginning of the year or before a military campaign, Roman magistrates used to consult the gods. Livy reports that the first admission of plebeians into a priestly college happened in 300 B.C. when the college of Augurs raised their number from four to nine. After that, plebeians were accepted into the other religious colleges, and by the end of the republic, only minor priesthoods with little political importance like the Salii, the Flamines and the Rex Sacrorum were exclusively filled by patricians. [PARAGRAPH:2]The distinction between patricians and plebeians in Ancient Rome was based purely on birth. Although modern writers often portray patricians as rich and powerful families who managed to secure power over the less-fortunate plebeian families, most historians argue that this is an over-simplification. As civil rights for plebeians increased during the middle and late Roman Republic, many plebeian families had attained wealth and power while some traditionally patrician families had fallen into poverty and obscurity.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PATRICIAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Bureaucracy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BUREAUCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Bureaucracy is a form of government in which a professional class manages the day to day operations of the government. They collect the taxes. They build the roads. They turn the ruler's wishes into actuality. The Chinese mandarins are an early example of a bureaucracy; the motor vehicle agency of your local government is a later example. [PARAGRAPH:2]Bureaucracies provide a certain amount of stability and competence to a government, ensuring that the government will continue to operate efficiently even if the old ruler is thrown out and a new and totally inexperienced ruler takes his or her place. Over time, though, a bureaucracy may become "entrenched" - growing in size and inefficiency to the point where it is extremely difficult for a leader to accomplish anything - good or ill.</English>
		<French>[TAB]La bureaucratie est une forme de gouvernement par laquelle une classe de professionnels dirige les op&#233;rations quotidiennes du gouvernement. Ils collectent les imp&#244;ts, construisent les routes et mettent en oeuvre les souhaits des dirigeants. Les mandarins chinois sont un des premiers exemples de bureaucratie. Les Directions R&#233;gionales du Commerce Ext&#233;rieur en sont un autre, plus r&#233;cent. [PARAGRAPH:2]La bureaucratie assure une certaine stabilit&#233; du pouvoir et met des comp&#233;tences au service des gouvernements. Ainsi, m&#234;me lorsqu'un dirigeant inexp&#233;riment&#233; arrive au pouvoir, le gouvernement continue de fonctionner avec une certaine efficacit&#233;. Cependant, la bureaucratie a tendance &#224; prolif&#233;rer et &#224; perdre en efficacit&#233;, au point de paralyser quelque peu le pouvoir et de l'emp&#234;cher de r&#233;aliser quoi que ce soit.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In einer B&#252;rokratie lenken Beamte im Namen eines Herrschers die Geschicke der Regierung. Sie erheben Steuern, bauen Stra&#223;en und setzen die Vorstellungen des Herrschers in die Tat um. Der chinesische Mandarin ist ebenso ein typischer Vertreter einer B&#252;rokratie, wie das Verkehrsamt einer Kommunalregierung. [PARAGRAPH:2]Eine B&#252;rokratie garantiert die Stabilit&#228;t und Kontinuit&#228;t einer Regierung und erm&#246;glicht auch nach deren Absetzung eine Fortsetzung der Regierungsgesch&#228;fte. Wird der b&#252;rokratische Apparat eines Landes zu gro&#223;, kann dies im Extremfall die v&#246;llige Handlungsunf&#228;higkeit des Staatsoberhauptes nach sich ziehen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La burocrazia &#232; una forma di gestione politica nella quale una classe di professionisti gestisce le operazioni quotidiane di un governo: si possono costruire strade, riscuotere le tasse, realizzare i desideri del proprio governante. I Mandarini Cinesi sono uno dei primi esempi di burocrazia; la motorizzazione civile delle nostre nazioni &#232; l'esempio della burocrazia odierna. [PARAGRAPH:2]Le burocrazie garantiscono la stabilit&#224; e la competenza di un governo, assicurandone il funzionamento efficiente persino nella successione tra un vecchio leader in favore di uno nuovo totalmente inesperto. Nel corso del tempo, la burocrazia pu&#242; trasformarsi in una "trincea": con l'espansione della burocrazia, infatti, aumenta di conseguenza l'inefficienza del sistema al punto che, per un leader, diventa impossibile compiere qualsiasi azione, nel bene e nel male.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La burocracia es una forma de gobierno en la que una clase profesional administra las tareas cotidianas del gobierno. Recauda los impuestos. Construye las carreteras. Convierte los deseos del gobernante en realidad. Los mandarines chinos representan un ejemplo antiguo de burocracia; el departamento de tr&#225;fico de cualquier municipio es un ejemplo m&#225;s moderno. [PARAGRAPH:2]La burocracia proporciona ciertas dosis de estabilidad y competencia a los gobiernos, y garantiza que contin&#250;en funcionando con eficacia aun cuando el gobernante es expulsado y reemplazado por alguien totalmente inexperto en las tareas de gobierno. Con el tiempo, tiende a "atrincherarse", esto es, a crecer y atrofiarse, hasta el punto de que los gobernantes acaban por tener dificultades para implantar cualquier medida, sea buena o mala.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BUREAUCRACY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Decreases maintenance costs from distance to Palace but number of cities has the opposite effect. +10% hammer, gold and science in all cities.</English>
		<French>Réduit le coût d'entretien lié à la distance, mais augmente le coût d'entretien lié au nombre de Villes. +10% production, or et science dans toutes les Villes.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Senate -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SENATE</Tag>
		<English>Senate</English>
		<French>Sénat</French>
		<German>Senat</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SENATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A senate is a deliberative assembly, often the upper house or chamber of a legislature or parliament. There have been many such bodies in history, since senate means the assembly of the eldest and wiser members of the society and ruling class. Two of the first official senates were the Spartan Gerousia and the Roman Senate. [PARAGRAPH:2]The members or legislators of a senate are called senators. The Latin word senator was adopted into English with no change in spelling. Its meaning is derived from a very ancient form of simple social organization in which decision-making powers are reserved for the eldest men. For the same reason, the word senate is correctly used when referring to any powerful authority characteristically composed by the eldest members of a community, as a deliberative body of a faculty in an institution of higher learning is often called a senate. The original senate was the Roman Senate, which lasted until 580 (various efforts to revive it were made in Medieval Rome). In the Eastern Roman Empire, the Byzantine Senate continued until the Fourth Crusade. [PARAGRAPH:2]Modern democratic states with bicameral parliamentary systems are sometimes equipped with a senate, often distinguished from an ordinary parallel lower house, known variously as the "House of Representatives", "House of Commons", "Chamber of Deputies", "National Assembly", "Legislative Assembly", or "House of Assembly", by electoral rules. This may include minimum age required for voters and candidates, proportional or majoritarian or plurality system, and an electoral basis or collegium. Typically, the senate is referred to as the upper house and has a smaller membership than the lower house. In some federal states senates also exist at the subnational level. In the United States all states other than Nebraska have a state senate. In Australia all states other than Queensland have an upper house known as a legislative council. Several Canadian provinces also once had legislative councils, but these have all been abolished, the last being Quebec's Legislative Council, in 1968. [PARAGRAPH:2]Senate membership can be determined either through elections or appointments. For example, elections are held every three years for half the membership of the Australian Senate, the term of a senator being six years. In contrast, members of the Canadian Senate are appointed by the Governor General upon the recommendation of the Prime Minister of Canada, holding the office until they resign, are removed, or retire at the mandatory age of 75. In larger countries, the senate often serves a balancing effect by giving a larger share of power to regions or groups which would otherwise be overwhelmed under strictly popular apportionment.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SENATE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Vassalage -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_VASSALAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Vassalage is a feudal term referring to a person who enters a contract with his or her lord, agreeing to serve and protect the lord in return for monetary rewards or ownership or sovereignty over a parcel of land. The contract is often of both political and religious significance binding both parties by the rules of man and of God. [PARAGRAPH:2]Vassalage is often tribal in nature. One tribe conquers another, and rather than killing the conquered tribe or taking over its direct management, the conquering ruler makes the conquered his vassal: the lower ruler continues to maintain control over his people and territory, while paying tribute to his or her lord in the form of money, goods, soldiers or slaves. </English>
		<French>[TAB]La vassalit&#233; est un terme f&#233;odal qui fait r&#233;f&#233;rence aux engagements pris entre des personnes et leur seigneur, l'un promettant de servir et de prot&#233;ger l'autre contre de l'argent, des biens ou m&#234;me la souverainet&#233; sur une parcelle de terres. Ce type de contrat a souvent &#224; la fois une signification politique et religieuse, les deux parties &#233;tant li&#233;es devant les hommes et devant Dieu. [PARAGRAPH:2]La vassalit&#233; est souvent tribale par nature. Une tribu en envahit une autre, mais plut&#244;t que de tuer tout le monde ou de s'emparer des r&#234;nes du pouvoir, le conqu&#233;rant fait du vaincu son vassal : ce dernier continue d'exercer le pouvoir sur son peuple, mais verse un tribut &#224; son seigneur sous la forme d'argent, de biens, de soldats ou d'esclaves. </French>
		<German>[TAB]Vasallen waren in der feudalen Gesellschaft Personen, die ihren Lehnsherren dienten oder diese besch&#252;tzten und f&#252;r ihre Dienste mit Geld, Grundbesitz oder Macht belohnt wurden. Der Vertrag zwischen Lehnsherr und Vasall hatte nicht selten eine politische oder religi&#246;se Bedeutung und war f&#252;r beide Parteien bindend.[PARAGRAPH:2]Das Vasallentum ist vor allem f&#252;r Stammeskulturen typisch. Erobert Stamm A beispielsweise Stamm B, wird Letzterer automatisch ein Vasall des Siegers. Der unterlegene Herrscher bleibt in diesem Fall im Amt und verpflichtet sich, seinen Bezwinger mit Geld, Waren, Soldaten oder Sklaven zu unterst&#252;tzen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il vassallaggio &#232; un termine feudale che si riferisce a una persona che stipula un contratto con il proprio signore, per proteggerlo e servirlo in cambio di ricompense monetarie, propriet&#224; o sovranit&#224; su una terra. Il contratto assume spesso un significato politico e religioso, legando entrambe le parti alle leggi umane e divine. [PARAGRAPH:2]Il vassallaggio assume spesso connotazioni di natura tribale. Una trib&#249; conquista un'altra e, invece di sterminarla o prendere il possesso della loro gestione, il vincitore della battaglia trasforma il perdente in un vassallo: il soggiogato continua a mantenere il controllo sulla propria gente e sul territorio, pagando per&#242; dei tributi sotto forma di soldi, beni, soldati o schiavi al proprio signore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Vasallaje es un t&#233;rmino feudal que hace referencia a la persona que establece una relaci&#243;n contractual con su se&#241;or en la que se compromete a servirlo y protegerlo a cambio de recompensas pecuniarias o de la propiedad (o usufructo) de una parcela. Normalmente, el contrato tiene connotaciones pol&#237;ticas y religiosas y somete a ambas partes a las leyes del hombre y de Dios.  [PARAGRAPH:2]El vasallaje suele ser de naturaleza tribal. Una tribu conquista a otra y, en vez de exterminarla o hacerse cargo de la administraci&#243;n directa de su patrimonio, convierte a los conquistados en vasallos: el gobernante sometido mantiene el control sobre su pueblo y su territorio, pero paga un tributo a su se&#241;or en forma de dinero, mercanc&#237;as, soldados o esclavos. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_VASSALAGE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>New units receive free experience points; lower unit support costs; +10% food and hammers in all cities; +20% commerce in all cities; +1 gold from Fortress; Increases unhealthy in all cities </English>
		<French>Les nouvelles unités recoivent de l'EXP; moins de coût d'entretien des unités; +10% Nourriture et production dans toutes les Villes; +20% commerce dans toutes les Villes; +1 Or de Forteresse; Réduit la Santé dans toutes les Villes</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Parliament -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PARLIAMENT</Tag>
		<English>Parliament</English>
		<French>Parlement</French>
		<German>Parlament</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PARLIAMENT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A parliament is a legislature, especially in those countries whose system of government is based on the Westminster system modeled after that of the United Kingdom. The name is derived from the French parlement, the action of parler (to speak): a parlement is a discussion. The term came to mean a meeting at which such a discussion took place. It acquired its modern meaning as it came to be used for the body of people (in an institutional sense) who would meet to discuss matters of state. [PARAGRAPH:2]The origins of the modern concept of prime ministerial government go back to the Kingdom of Great Britain (1707 - 1800) and The Parliamentary System in Sweden 1721 - 1772 , that coincided with each other. [PARAGRAPH:2]In theory, power resided in the monarch, who chaired cabinet and chose ministers. In reality, King George I's inability to speak English led the responsibility for chairing cabinet to go to the leading minister, literally the prime or first minister. The gradual democratisation of parliament with the broadening of the voting franchise increased parliament's role in controlling government, and in deciding who the king could ask to form a government. By the nineteenth century, the Great Reform Act of 1832 led to parliamentary dominance, with its choice invariably deciding who was prime minister and the complexion of the government.[PARAGRAPH:2]Other countries gradually adopted what came to be called the Westminster Model of government, with an executive answerable to parliament, but exercising powers nominally vested in the head of state, in the name of the head of state. Hence the use of phrases like Her Majesty's government or His Excellency's government. Such a system became particularly prevalent in older British dominions, many of whom had their constitutions enacted by the British parliament. Examples include Australia, New Zealand, Canada, the Irish Free State and the Union of South Africa, though these parliaments themselves have often evolved or were reformed from their British model: the Australian Senate, for instance, more closely reflects the US Senate than the British House of Lords; whereas there is no upper house in New Zealand.[PARAGRAPH:2]In very ancient India, during the Vedic civilization, there are mentions of two Parliament-like gatherings of the Indo-Aryan kingdoms called the Sabha and the Samiti. During the time of the Buddha, many states were even tribal republics, called the Sanghas. The Sabha has been interpreted by the historians as a representative assembly of the elect-the important men of the clan, which ran day-to-day business with the king. The Samiti seems to be a gathering of all the male members of the kingdom, and probably convened only for the ratification/election of a new king. The two largely democratic institutions, which kept a check on the absolutism of the king, were given a sacred position, and have been called the daughters of the deity Prajapati in the Vedas, the holiest of all Hindu scriptures and the earliest Indo-European literature. However, these democratic institutions became weaker as republics became larger and elected chieftainship moved towards hereditary and absolute monarchy. The Sabha and the Samiti bear almost no mention in later literature. After this, India would not have any democratic legislature till the British times, culminating in its modern democratic Parliament (whose two Houses still bear the name of Sabha).</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PARLIAMENT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- President -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRESIDENT</Tag>
		<English>President</English>
		<French>Président</French>
		<German>Pr&#228;sident</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRESIDENT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>President is a title held by many leaders of organizations, companies, trade unions, universities, and countries. Etymologically, a "president" is one who presides, who sits in leadership. Originally, the term referred to the presiding officer of a ceremony or meeting (i.e., chairman), but today it most commonly refers to an official. Among other things, president today is a common title for the heads of state of most republics, whether popularly elected, chosen by the legislature or by a special electoral college. It is also often adopted by dictators. [PARAGRAPH:2]As an English word, the term was originally used to refer to the presiding officer of a committee or governing body in Great Britain. Early examples are the President of the Exchequer ("presidentis" in the original Latin, from the Dialogue concerning the Exchequer, 1179), the presidents of the universities of Oxford and Cambridge (from 1464), and the founding President of the Royal Society (William Brouncker, 1660). [PARAGRAPH:2]Later this usage was applied to political leaders, including the leaders of some of the Thirteen Colonies (originally Virginia in 1608); in full, the "President of the Council". The first president of a country was George Washington, the President of the United States. In America the title was "upgraded" from its earlier use for the President of the Continental Congress, the "officer in charge of the Continental Congress" since 1774. As other countries deposed their monarchies and became republics, president was commonly adopted as the title for the head of state. The first European president was the president of France, a post created in the Second Republic of 1848. The first president of an internationally recognized African state was the President of Liberia in 1848. Today, most republics have a President as their head of state.[PARAGRAPH:2]In states with a presidential system of government, the president exercises the functions of Head of State and Head of Government, i.e. he or she directs the executive branch of government.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRESIDENT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Society Civics Option +++ -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_SOCIETY</Tag>
		<English>Society</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_ABBR_SOCIETY</Tag>
		<English>Soc.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Unstructured -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNSTRUCTURED</Tag>
		<English>Unstructured</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNSTRUCTURED_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]There is no real structure to society or even much concept of it.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le tribalisme est une forme d'organisation qui place au-dessus de tout le bien-&#234;tre de la tribu. Les individus n'ont pas de droits, les hommes et les femmes n'existent que pour le bien de la tribu. Le tribalisme est une forme de gouvernement assez efficace pour de petits groupes de gens dont la survie est pr&#233;caire. Dans la tribu, tout le monde se conna&#238;t. On sait parfaitement qui est fort, intelligent ou habile. [PARAGRAPH:2]Les dirigeants sont g&#233;n&#233;ralement d&#233;sign&#233;s au m&#233;rite, selon les besoins de la tribu : si la tribu a faim, le chef sera le meilleur chasseur, si elle est attaqu&#233;e, le meilleur guerrier prend les commandes, et ainsi de suite. Une tribu doit savoir d&#233;signer les bons dirigeants, sinon elle dispara&#238;t. [PARAGRAPH:2]Le tribalisme ne survit pas &#224; l'accroissement de la population. Les gens de la m&#234;me tribu ne se connaissent plus, des groupes (ou factions) se forment, et la population ne partage plus les m&#234;mes aspirations. La tribu doit alors se trouver une autre forme de gouvernement, ou se fractionner en petits groupes.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNSTRUCTURED_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Workers have littl eguidance and are less productive.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Tribal -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TRIBAL</Tag>
		<English>Tribal Law</English>
		<French>Loi Tribale</French>
		<German>Stammesgesetz</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TRIBAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Tribalism is a form of organization which emphasizes the tribe as the sole unit of importance. Individuals have no rights; each man, woman and child exists only to support the tribe.  Tribalism is a fairly useful form of government for a small group of people who exist on the edge of catastrophe. In a tribe everyone knows everybody else; who is strong and who is weak, who is intelligent and who is not, who is skilled and who is unskilled. [PARAGRAPH:2]Leadership in the tribe is usually determined by merit, according to the tribe's needs: if the tribe is hungry, the best hunter becomes the leader. If the tribe is surrounded by enemies, the best warrior is chosen. And so forth. A tribe must quickly learn how to pick successful leaders; otherwise it will perish. [PARAGRAPH:2]Tribalism tends to break down when the tribe becomes overly large. People no longer know everyone in their tribe. Groups (or factions) appear, and everyone no longer share the same objectives. The tribe must find a more sophisticated system of government or fracture into smaller squabbling units.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le tribalisme est une forme d'organisation qui place au-dessus de tout le bien-&#234;tre de la tribu. Les individus n'ont pas de droits, les hommes et les femmes n'existent que pour le bien de la tribu. Le tribalisme est une forme de gouvernement assez efficace pour de petits groupes de gens dont la survie est pr&#233;caire. Dans la tribu, tout le monde se conna&#238;t. On sait parfaitement qui est fort, intelligent ou habile. [PARAGRAPH:2]Les dirigeants sont g&#233;n&#233;ralement d&#233;sign&#233;s au m&#233;rite, selon les besoins de la tribu : si la tribu a faim, le chef sera le meilleur chasseur, si elle est attaqu&#233;e, le meilleur guerrier prend les commandes, et ainsi de suite. Une tribu doit savoir d&#233;signer les bons dirigeants, sinon elle dispara&#238;t. [PARAGRAPH:2]Le tribalisme ne survit pas &#224; l'accroissement de la population. Les gens de la m&#234;me tribu ne se connaissent plus, des groupes (ou factions) se forment, et la population ne partage plus les m&#234;mes aspirations. La tribu doit alors se trouver une autre forme de gouvernement, ou se fractionner en petits groupes.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Innerhalb eines Stammessystems ist allein der Stamm von Bedeutung. Der Einzelne genie&#223;t keinerlei Rechte. Jedes Stammesmitglied (ob Mann, Frau oder Kind) ist verpflichtet, den Stamm zu unterst&#252;tzen. F&#252;r eine sehr kleine Gruppe von Menschen kann das Stammessystem eine praktikable Regierungsform sein, da jeder die St&#228;rken und Schw&#228;chen des anderen kennt und dessen individuelle F&#228;higkeiten einzusch&#228;tzen wei&#223;. [PARAGRAPH:2]Das Stammesoberhaupt wird meist aufgrund seiner Verdienste bestimmt, die sich wiederum an den Bed&#252;rfnissen des Stammes orientieren. Hungert der Stamm, wird der beste J&#228;ger zum Stammesoberhaupt ernannt. Ist der Stamm von Feinden umgeben, w&#228;hlt man den besten Krieger als Stammesoberhaupt aus. Gelingt es einem Stamm nicht, ein Stammesoberhaupt zu bestimmen, ist er meist dem Untergang geweiht. [PARAGRAPH:2]Das Stammessystem bricht im Allgemeinen auseinander, wenn der Stamm zu gro&#223; wird und pl&#246;tzlich Einzelgruppen pers&#246;nliche Ziele verfolgen. Ist dies der Fall, muss der Stamm ein komplexeres Regierungssystem finden oder sich in verschiedene Gruppen aufspalten.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]L'organizzazione tribale &#232; una forma di ordinamento che enfatizza l'importanza totale della trib&#249;. Gli individui non hanno diritti: uomini, donne e bambini esistono unicamente per sostentare la trib&#249;. L'organizzazione tribale &#232; un tipo di governo adatto a piccoli gruppi di persone che vivono sull'orlo del baratro. In una trib&#249;, tutti si conoscono, chi &#232; forte e chi &#232; debole, chi &#232; intelligente e chi no, chi &#232; abile e chi &#232; inesperto. [PARAGRAPH:2]Il comando di una trib&#249; viene in genere determinato per merito, a seconda dei bisogni del gruppo: se la trib&#249; &#232; affamata, il miglior cacciatore diventa il capo, se la trib&#249; &#232; assediata dal nemico, viene scelto il miglior guerriero, e via discorrendo. Una trib&#249; deve imparare velocemente a saper riconoscere il leader pi&#249; adatto, altrimenti rischia di perire. [PARAGRAPH:2]L'organizzazione tribale tende a disgregarsi quando aumentano gli individui del gruppo e non tutti si conoscono pi&#249; tra loro; appaiono cos&#236; gruppi (o fazioni) e la gente non condivide pi&#249; gli stessi obiettivi. La trib&#249; deve a quel punto trovare un nuovo sistema di governo pi&#249; sofisticato oppure divedersi in piccoli gruppi in perenne disputa.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El tribalismo es una forma de sociedad en la que la tribu es el &#250;nico elemento importante. Los individuos carecen de derechos; los hombres, mujeres y ni&#241;os solo existen para apoyar a la tribu.  Se trata de una forma de gobierno muy &#250;til para un grupo peque&#241;o de gente que vive bajo la constante amenaza de la extinci&#243;n. En una tribu todos se conocen: se sabe qui&#233;n es fuerte y qui&#233;n es d&#233;bil, qui&#233;n es inteligente y qui&#233;n no lo es, qui&#233;n es h&#225;bil y qui&#233;n no. [PARAGRAPH:2]El liderazgo suele determinarse por un sistema de m&#233;ritos adaptado a las necesidades de la tribu; si el hambre es un problema, el mejor cazador se convierte en l&#237;der. Si la tribu est&#225; rodeada de enemigos, se elige al mejor guerrero. Y as&#237; sucesivamente. La tribu debe aprender a elegir buenos l&#237;deres; de lo contrario, est&#225; condenada a la desaparici&#243;n. [PARAGRAPH:2]El tribalismo suele dejar de funcionar cuando la tribu crece en exceso. Los miembros de la tribu ya no se conocen. Aparecen grupos (o facciones) y todos dejan de compartir los mismos objetivos. Entonces la tribu debe encontrar un sistema de gobierno m&#225;s sofisticado o fraccionarse en unidades m&#225;s peque&#241;as y hostiles entre s&#237;.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TRIBAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Distance maintenance costs lowered by 50%. Slightly increased production in all cities.</English>
		<French>Coût d'entretien lié à la distance réduit de 50%. Augmente la production dans toutes les Villes.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Caste -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CASTE_SYSTEM</Tag>
		<English>Caste</English>
		<French>Castes</French>
		<German>Kastenwesen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CASTE_SYSTEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The caste system is one where one's parentage determines one's place in society. If your parents are street-cleaners, then so are you. If your parents are merchants, that's what you are. If your parents are nobility, then you are as well. Your status is determined at birth, and there's nothing you can do to better it. One may advance within one's caste, but that's as far as it goes. Marriages between castes are taboo. [PARAGRAPH:2]There is little advantage to the caste system, except to the people whose parents are on the top of the heap. Merit and initiative are useless: if the most intelligent and wise person in the culture happens to be born a street-cleaner, then he'll be an intelligent and wise street-cleaner. He'll never have a chance to become a priest, philosopher, or leader.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Dans un syst&#232;me de castes, la parent&#233; d&#233;termine la position de chacun au sein de la soci&#233;t&#233;. Si vos parents &#233;taient des &#233;boueurs, vous serez donc &#233;boueur, s'ils &#233;taient marchands, vous le serez aussi. Votre position sociale est d&#233;termin&#233;e &#224; la naissance, et vous ne pouvez absolument rien y changer. Vous pourrez progresser au sein de votre caste, mais jamais passer dans une caste sup&#233;rieure. Les mariages inter-castes sont tabous. [PARAGRAPH:2]Le syst&#232;me des castes n'a que peu d'avantages, si ce n'est pour les gens dont les parents sont en haut de la hi&#233;rarchie sociale. Le m&#233;rite et l'initiative ne sont pas r&#233;compens&#233;s : une personne intelligente et sage qui est n&#233;e &#233;boueur, ne sera jamais qu'un &#233;boueur intelligent et sage. Il ne deviendra jamais pr&#234;tre, philosophe ou dirigeant politique.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In Kastensystemen bestimmt die Herkunft den Platz eines Menschen innerhalb der Gesellschaft. Sind die Eltern eines Kindes Stra&#223;enkehrer, wird auch das Kind ein Stra&#223;enkehrer. Sind sie Mechaniker, wird auch das Kind Mechaniker. Da der Status eines Menschen bereits bei dessen Geburt festgelegt wird, kann er nichts tun, um diesen zu verbessern. Lediglich Fortschritte innerhalb der eigenen Kaste sind m&#246;glich. Die Ehe mit einem Mitglied einer anderen Kaste ist tabu. [PARAGRAPH:2]Das Kastensystem ist nur f&#252;r Angeh&#246;rige der oberen Kasten von Vorteil. Leistung und Eigeninitiative sind ohne Bedeutung. Wird der kl&#252;gste und weiseste Mensch des Landes als Stra&#223;enkehrer geboren, wird aus ihm ein kluger und weiser Stra&#223;enkehrer, niemals aber ein Priester, Philosoph oder Staatsoberhaupt. </German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La casta &#232; un sistema nel quale la propria posizione sociale &#232; determinata dalla discendenza. Se i tuoi genitori sono degli spazzini, mercanti o nobili, lo sei anche tu. Il tuo stato sociale &#232; determinato alla nascita e non c'&#232; nulla che si possa fare per cambiarlo; si pu&#242; migliorare la propria posizione all'interno della casta e i matrimoni tra caste differenti sono vietati. [PARAGRAPH:2]Non ci sono molti vantaggi in un sistema a caste, tranne per coloro i cui genitori sono in cima alla piramide. Il merito e l'iniziativa sono inutili: se una persona intelligente e saggia nasce spazzino, sar&#224; uno spazzino saggio e intelligente; non avr&#224; mai la possibilit&#224; di diventare un sacerdote, un filosofo o un leader.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]En el sistema de castas, lo que determina el lugar que uno ocupa en la sociedad es su nacimiento.  Si tus padres son barrenderos, t&#250; tambi&#233;n. Si tus padres son mercaderes, eso ser&#225;s t&#250;. Si tus padres son nobles, noble eres t&#250; tambi&#233;n. El estatus personal se determina en el momento del nacimiento y no se puede hacer nada por modificarlo. Uno puede avanzar en el seno de su propia casta, pero nada m&#225;s. Los matrimonios entre diferentes castas est&#225;n prohibidos. [PARAGRAPH:2]Este sistema no posee apenas ventajas, salvo para los que pertenecen a la casta superior. Los m&#233;ritos y la capacidad no sirven de nada: si la persona m&#225;s inteligente y sabia del mundo tiene la desgracia de nacer en una familia de barrenderos, ser&#225; un inteligente y sabio barrendero. Nunca podr&#225; llegar a ser sacerdote, fil&#243;sofo o gobernante.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CASTE_SYSTEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Proletariat -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PROLETARIAT</Tag>
		<English>Proletariat</English>
		<French>Prolétariat</French>
		<German>Proletariat</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PROLETARIAT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Proletariat represents a society ruled by proletariats, otherwise known as the lower or working class. Under such a society, the interests of the proletariats are regarded as more important than that of the bourgeois. Early in history, a Proletariat society would place production of buildings necessary for farmers and artisans in top priority, and in modern times a Proletariat society would build public works more cheaply. Modern liberalism, populism and progressivism are modern examples of Proletariat ideology.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PROLETARIAT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Bourgeois -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BOURGEOIS</Tag>
		<English>Bourgeois</English>
		<French>Bourgeois</French>
		<German>Bourgeois</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BOURGEOIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Bourgeois describes a range of groups across history. In the Western world, between the late 18th century to now, the bourgeoisie are a social class of people, characterized by their ownership of capital and their related culture. They are a part of the middle or merchant classes, and derived social and economic power from employment, education, and wealth, as distinguished from social classes whose power came from being born into an aristocratic family of titled land owners granted feudal privileges by the monarch. The bourgeoisie emerged from late feudal and early modern towns, through the control of long distance trade and petty manufacture. Bourgeois and bourgeoisie originate in the French language, meaning "city-dweller".</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BOURGEOIS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Bourgeois increases culture in all cities and few improvements produce more gold. Decreases the production cost of several building types and affects building happiness.</English>
		<French>Les Bourgeois augmentent la culture dans toutes les Villes and et certaines améliorations de terrain produisent plus d'or. Diminue le coût de production et les bonus de moral de certains bâtiments.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Feudal -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FEUDAL</Tag>
		<English>Feudal</English>
		<French>Féodal</French>
		<German>Feudal</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FEUDAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Feudal in most instances represents the social structure used during the Medieval period. It consists of peasants bound by contract as serfs to lords. The lords own manors with large amounts of farmland which the serfs work for payment and protection. However, as demonstrated by Friedrich Hayek in his novel Road to Serfdom, the practices of economic central-planning governments can lead to a modern form of feudalism, replacing the lords with the government and the serfs with all citizens.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FEUDAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Liberal -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_LIBERAL</Tag>
		<English>Liberal</English>
		<French>Libéral</French>
		<German>Liberal</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_LIBERAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Liberal represents the liberal political ideology. A liberal society regards civil liberties, free speech and being the best you can be with great worth.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_LIBERAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Nationalist -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_NATIONALIST</Tag>
		<English>Nationalist</English>
		<French>Nationaliste</French>
		<German>Nationalistisch</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_NATIONALIST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Nationalist represents a society that believes people should work and fight for their country over themselves. Nationalism leads to a higher number of volunteer soldiers, less anger over conscription, and less anger over a long war. However, nationalism also leads to a large sense of nativism and a lack of acceptance of buying imports.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_NATIONALIST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Marxist -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MARXIST</Tag>
		<English>Marxist</English>
		<French>Marxiste</French>
		<German>Marxistisch</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MARXIST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Marxist represents a society that believes capitalism exploits workers and believes in an abolition of social class structure. Marxism is often considered to be what led to the creation of communism, socialism and planned economies.</English>
		<French>Marxiste représente une société qui pense que le Capitalisme exploite les Ouvriers et milite pour l'abolition de la structure des classes sociales. Le Marxisme est souvent considéré comme le précurseur du Communisme, Socialisme, et de l'Economie planifiée.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MARXIST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Military Civics Option +++ -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_MILITARY</Tag>
		<English>Military</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_ABBR_MILITARY</Tag>
		<English>Mil.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Banditry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BANDITS</Tag>
		<English>Banditry</English>
		<French>Banditisme</French>
		<German>Banditenwesen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BANDITS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Banditry is a weak form of military, typically associated weak city-state governments. Bandits do not often form large groups and generally ignore the provisions of government. For these reasons it is nearly impossible to successfully base a powerful military off of bandits due to their solitary behavior and mistrust of all.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BANDITS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Conscription -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CONSCRIPTION1</Tag>
		<English>Conscription</English>
		<French>Conscription</French>
		<German>Wehrpflicht</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CONSCRIPTION1_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Conscription is a forced tour of duty in a military service. It is often employed where the ruler rules with absolute power over the civilian population. Because the service is generally not voluntary, many may find the military service disagreeable and lacking in quality.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CONSCRIPTION1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can build a [LINK=BUILDING_DRAFT_OFFICE]Draft Office[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut Construire un [LINK=BUILDING_DRAFT_OFFICE]Bureau de recrutement[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kein ein [LINK=BUILDING_DRAFT_OFFICE]Einberufungsbüro[\LINK] errichten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CONSCRIPTION1_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Vassals -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FUEDALISM</Tag>
		<English>Vassalage</English>
		<French>Vassal</French>
		<German>Vasallentum</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FUEDALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A vassal is one who enters into mutual obligations with a monarch, usually of military support and mutual protection, in exchange for certain guarantees, which came to include the terrain held as a fief. By analogy it is applied to similar systems in other feudal societies. It was always distinct from fidelitas, sworn loyalty of subject to king, and the honor, the respect and consideration that accrued to the vassal, unlike the delegated power of a comes or count, was not expressed in expectations of related public duty.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FUEDALISM_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can build a [LINK=BUILDING_SHANTYTOWN]Shanty Town[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut construire un [LINK=BUILDING_SHANTYTOWN]Bidon-ville[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann eine [LINK=BUILDING_SHANTYTOWN]Barrackenstadt[\LINK] errichten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FUEDALISM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Standing Army -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STANDING_ARMY</Tag>
		<English>Standing Army</English>
		<French>Armée de Métier</French>
		<German>Stehende Armee</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STANDING_ARMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Standing Armies are large armies that remain always active for military service, regardless of the current diplomatic situation. Standing armies are useful when responding to quickly changing threats, but come at a high cost to the owner.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STANDING_ARMY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can build a [LINK=BUILDING_MARCHING_PAVILION]Parade Grounds[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut Construire un [LINK=BUILDING_MARCHING_PAVILION]Terrain de Parade[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann einen [LINK=BUILDING_MARCHING_PAVILION]Paradeplatz[\LINK] errichten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STANDING_ARMY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Volunteer Army -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_VOLUNTEER_ARMY</Tag>
		<English>Volunteer Army</English>
		<French>Armée de Volontaires</French>
		<German>Freiwilligenarmee</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_VOLUNTEER_ARMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Volunteer armies are based completely off of volunteers. This has many advantages to the older conscription style armies, as volunteers are much more likely to be skilled and want to serve in the military, greatly improving morale. The largest downside is that during prolonged conflicts, volunteers may become scarce and the army size may dwindle.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_VOLUNTEER_ARMY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can build a [LINK=BUILDING_RECRUITMENT_OFFICE]Recruitment office[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut construire un[LINK=BUILDING_RECRUITMENT_OFFICE]Bureau d'Engagement[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann ein [LINK=BUILDING_RECRUITMENT_OFFICE]Rekrutierungsbüro[\LINK] errichten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_VOLUNTEER_ARMY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Pacifism -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PACIFISM</Tag>
		<English>Pacifism</English>
		<French>Pacifisme</French>
		<German>Pazifismus</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PACIFISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Pacifism is the opposition to war or violence as a means of settling disputes or gaining advantage. Pacifism covers a spectrum of views ranging from the belief that international disputes can and should be peacefully resolved; to calls for the abolition of the institutions of the military and war; to opposition to any organization of society through governmental force; to rejection of the use of physical violence to obtain political, economic or social goals; to the condemnation of force except in cases where it is absolutely necessary to advance the cause of peace; to opposition to violence under any circumstance, including defense of self and others.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PACIFISM_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can build an [LINK=BUILDING_ART_GALLERY]Art Gallery[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut construire une [LINK=BUILDING_ART_GALLERY]Galerie d'Art[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann eine [LINK=BUILDING_ART_GALLERY]Kunstgallerie[\LINK] erbauen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PACIFISM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- M.A.D -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MUTUALLY_ASSURED_DESTRUCTION</Tag>
		<English>M.A.D</English>
		<French>M.A.D</French>
		<German>Abschreckung</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MUTUALLY_ASSURED_DESTRUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Mutually Assured Destruction (M.A.D) is a doctrine of military strategy in which a full-scale use of nuclear weapons by two opposing sides would effectively result in the destruction of both the attacker and the defender. It is based on the theory of deterrence according to which the development of strong weapons is essential to threaten the enemy in order to prevent the use of the very same weapons.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MUTUALLY_ASSURED_DESTRUCTION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can build a [LINK=BUILDING_MISSILE_SILO]Missile Lab[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut construire un [LINK=BUILDING_MISSILE_SILO]Silo de Missiles[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann ein [LINK=BUILDING_MISSILE_SILO]Raketenlabor[\LINK] errichten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MUTUALLY_ASSURED_DESTRUCTION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Unmanned Warfare -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNMANNED_WARFARE</Tag>
		<English>Unmanned Warfare</English>
		<French>Armée droïde</French>
		<German>Unbemannte Kriegsführung</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNMANNED_WARFARE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Unmanned Warfare is the culmination of weapon science and pacifism. It allows the military to control operations remotely, without the potiental loss of life, or at least, friendly life. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNMANNED_WARFARE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can build a [LINK=BUILDING_CONTROL_CENTER]Control Center[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]peut construire un [LINK=BUILDING_CONTROL_CENTER]Centre de Contrôle[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann ein [LINK=BUILDING_CONTROL_CENTER]Kontrollzentrum[\LINK] errichten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNMANNED_WARFARE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	
<!-- +++ Religion Civics Option +++ -->
	<TEXT> <!-- Pre-belief -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRE_BELIEF</Tag>
		<English>Pre-belief</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRE_BELIEF_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The is no structured belief system in place.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRE_BELIEF_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>With no belief structure there is no place in early society for the advancement of great people.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Folklore -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FOLKLORE</Tag>
		<English>Folklore</English>
		<French>Folklore</French>
		<German>Folklore</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FOLKLORE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Folklore represents primitive religion system. Paganism and shamanism is common and people often worship things like nature and weather gods, spirits and other supernatural things.</English>
		<French>Le Folklore représente le système primitif de religion. Paganisme et Shamanisme est courant, et le peuple vénère des dieux de la nature et du temps, les esptits et autres choses surnaturelles.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FOLKLORE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Prophets -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PROPHETS</Tag>
		<English>Prophets</English>
		<French>Prophètes</French>
		<German>Propheten</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PROPHETS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Prophets represents religion spreading through the orations of wandering prophets. The state is too primitive at this point in order to control the spread of religion, so religions spread easily throughout your civilization and foreign civilizations geographically near you.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PROPHETS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Divine Cult -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DIVINE_RULE</Tag>
		<English>Divine Cult</English>
		<French>Culte Divin</French>
		<German>Gotteskult</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DIVINE_RULE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Divine Cult represents a state-run cult that forces all citizens to worship the civilizations rulers as gods. The state uses this religion as justification for military campaigns. A classic example of a civilization employing an divine cult is ancient Egypt and modern North Korea.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DIVINE_RULE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- State Church -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STATE_CHURCH</Tag>
		<English>State Church</English>
		<French>Eglise d'Etat</French>
		<German>Staatskirche</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STATE_CHURCH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>State Church represents a religion run by a church that is owned and operated by the government. In a theocracy, the clergy have power over the state, but in a state church the state has power over the clergy. Similarly to Free Church, the church is powerful and has influence on the civilization. However, commerce and trade increases in the capital city rather than the holy city due to the states centralization of religion.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STATE_CHURCH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Free Church -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FREE_CHURCH</Tag>
		<English>Free Church</English>
		<French>Eglise Libre</French>
		<German>Freie Kirche</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FREE_CHURCH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Free Church represents a strong central church that is independent from the state. Technically, the state has authority over the church, but the church is often exhibits more power than the state. In some cases, a strong free church can infiltrate the state and employ theocracy, but not in all cases. An example of a strong free church is the Roman Catholic church during the Medieval era.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FREE_CHURCH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Intolerant -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_INTOLERANT</Tag>
		<English>Intolerant</English>
		<French>Intolérant</French>
		<German>Intolerant</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_INTOLERANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Intolerant represents a society that is extremely intolerant of all non-state religions and scientific research that could undermine their religion. An intolerant society, with the help of the church and/or the state, eradicates all non-state religions in your civilization through an inquisition. In addition, all soldiers are conditioned to fight to the death for their religion and are guaranteed a good afterlife if they do so. Intolerant is great for creating a massive religious military campaign, known as a crusade or holy war, but completely undermines all scientific and technological advancement. Examples of intolerance are Europe during the Crusades, the Spanish Inquisition, and modern Islamic Jihadists.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_INTOLERANT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Secular -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SECULAR</Tag>
		<English>Secular</English>
		<French>Séculier</French>
		<German>S&#228;kular</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SECULAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Secular represents a complete separation of church and state. Specific religions are given no special benefits from the state and all religions are accepted and guaranteed rights in the civilization. An example is the United States.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SECULAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Atheist -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ATHEIST</Tag>
		<English>Atheist</English>
		<French>Athé</French>
		<German>Atheistisch</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ATHEIST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Atheist represents a society with a distrust of all religions and atheism set as the state religion. Religions are not allowed to hold public displays nor try to convert others to their religion, which angers anyone who practices a religion. However, religions are allowed to preach and exhibit their history on the radio and in plays, which helps balance the unhappiness.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ATHEIST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Atheist increases taxes and science in all cities and all specialists get +1 culture. Government doesn't allow state religion and religions are not allowed to spread to your cities.</English>
		<French>Augmente les Taxes et la Science dans toutes les Villes et tous les Spécialistes ont +1 en culture. Ce Gouvernment ne permet pas de religion d'état et les religions ne peuvent pas se propager dans vos Villes.</French>
	</TEXT>

<!-- +++ Welfare Civics Options +++ -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_WELFARE</Tag>
		<English>Welfare</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVICOPTION_ABBR_WELFARE</Tag>
		<English>Wel.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Charity -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHARITY</Tag>
		<English>Charity</English>
		<French>Charité</French>
		<German>Wohlfahrt</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHARITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Charity represents unorganized charity as a means of welfare for the poor. Local healers and generous wealthy farmers are the source of welfare for most poor people.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHARITY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Charity gives +1 happiness from Granary and Modern Granary and increases health from Healer's Hut, Doctor's Office and Bazaar.</English>
		<French>Augmente le Bonheur de 1 en raison de Grenier, et augmente la Santé de la hutte du Guérisseur, le Cabinet de médecin et le Bazar.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Church -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHURCH</Tag>
		<English>Church</English>
		<French>Eglise</French>
		<German>Kirche</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHURCH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Church represents welfare supplied by the church. People who attend religious ceremonies and prayer put food into a charity box and the poor can come to collect food if they need it.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CHURCH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Church increases health by 1 in all cities and every religions' Monastery will increase city's health by 1. Improvements upgrade faster and cities with state religion can construct buildings faster.</English>
		<French>Augmente la Santé de 1 dans toutes les Villes et chaque monastère augmente la Santé de 1. Le Aménagements se développent plus vite et les Villes avec la religion d'étant peuvent construire les bâtiments plus vite.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Corporate -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CORPORATE</Tag>
		<English>Corporate</English>
		<French>Corporations</French>
		<German>Korporiert</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CORPORATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Corporate represents the government using tax money to help corporations expand and maintain themselves.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CORPORATE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Corporatist increases maintenance costs from number of cities by 25% but corporations maintenance costs are reduced by 35%. Increases health by 3 and science by 15% in all cities but causes unhappiness in largest cities. Corporation buildings are cheaper to build.</English>
		<French>Augmente le coût d'entretien lié au nombre de Villes de 25%, mais le coût d'entretien des corporations est réduit de 35%. Augmente la Santé de 3 et la Science de 15% dans toutes les Villes, mais engendre du mécontentement dans les plus grandes villes. Les bâtiments des corporations sont plus rapidement construits.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Private -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRIVATE</Tag>
		<English>Private</English>
		<French>Privé</French>
		<German>Privat</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRIVATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Private represents organized private charity as a means of welfare for the poor. Wealthy merchants and corporate executives, due to moral beliefs or to create a reputation of generosity, give money and food to charity organizations and fund research projects that could benefit the poor.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PRIVATE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Public Works -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PUBLIC_WORKS</Tag>
		<English>Public Works</English>
		<French>Travaux Publics</French>
		<German>&#214;ffentliche Bauvorhaben</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PUBLIC_WORKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Public Works represents the government using tax money to fund public infrastructure.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PUBLIC_WORKS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]-25%% [LINK=BUILDING_PAVED_ROADS]Paved Roads[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_SEWER_SYSTEM]Sewer System[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_PUBLIC_TRANSPORTATION]Public Transportation[\LINK] and [LINK=BUILDING_PERSONAL_RAPID_TRAIN]Personal Rapid Train[\LINK] Cost</English>
		<French>ICON_BULLET]Coût de production de -25%% pour : [LINK=BUILDING_PAVED_ROADS]Routes pavées[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_SEWER_SYSTEM]Sewer Système d'égoûts[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_PUBLIC_TRANSPORTATION]Transports en Commun[\LINK] et [LINK=BUILDING_PERSONAL_RAPID_TRAIN]Train Rapide Personnel[\LINK].</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]-25%% Kosten f&#252;r[LINK=BUILDING_PAVED_ROADS]Gepflasterte Stra&#223;en[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_SEWER_SYSTEM]Kanalisation[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_PUBLIC_TRANSPORTATION]&#214;ffentlicher Nahverkehr[\LINK] und [LINK=BUILDING_PERSONAL_RAPID_TRAIN]Individueller Schnellzug[\LINK]</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PUBLIC_WORKS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Socialised -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SOCIALIZED</Tag>
		<English>Socialised</English>
		<French>Sécurité Sociale</French>
		<German>Sozial</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SOCIALIZED_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Socialised represents the government giving free universal healthcare and free universal college educations to all citizens. Socialised welfare makes the bulk of society very happy (except the top 5%) and very healthy, but removes many industries from the market, and the ridiculous tax rate harms commerce dramatically.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SOCIALIZED_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Subsidised -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUBSIDIZED</Tag>
		<English>Subsidised</English>
		<French>Subventionnés</French>
		<German>Subventionen</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUBSIDIZED_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Subsidised represents the government putting in place a progressive income tax where the rich pay higher taxes and the revenue is used to subsidise low income housing, food stamps, etc. Also included is free public education for elementary, primary, and secondary school for children, which puts more people into the fields of science and business.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SUBSIDIZED_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The healthcare system is additional funded by tax income from the government. +1 [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]health[COLOR_REVERT] to all of your cities. Eliminates [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]unhealthiness[COLOR_REVERT] from buildings. +1 [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]food[COLOR_REVERT] from your [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]towns[COLOR_REVERT]</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Survival -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SURVIVAL</Tag>
		<English>Survival</English>
		<French>Survie</French>
		<German>&#220;berlebenskampf</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SURVIVAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Survival represents welfare system where everyone cares only about his/her own family's survival. This behaviour often results in barbaric actions where people decide to seek out and plunder neighbour tribes.</English>
		<French>Survie représent un système de bien-être où les seules préoccupations sont la survie de sa famille. Ce comportement a généralement des conséquences dramatiques et se caractérise par des actions barbares comme le génocide et  l'extermintation des tribus voisines.</French>
		<German>Der &#220;berlebenskampf repr&#228;sentiert ein Wohlfahrtssystem, in dem jeder sich nur das eigene &#220;berleben oder das seiner Familie k&#252;mmert. Dieses Verhalten f&#252;hrt oft zu gezielten Pl&#252;nderungen von Nachbarst&#228;mmen und vielf&#228;ltigen F&#228;llen von Barbarei.</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SURVIVAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>.</English>
	</TEXT>

</Civ4GameText>
