<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT> <!-- Capital Seat -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_SEAT</Tag>
		<English>Capital Seat</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_SEAT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The capital seat is the location where the leader of the civ parks his behind and defines the capital of the civilisation before the advent of more permanent structures such as palaces.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_SEAT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Capital Seat[COLOR_REVERT] defines the capital and administrative centre of a civilzation and also provides a small production bonus.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<!-- Cave Painting -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAVE_PAINTING</Tag>
		<English>Cave Painting</English>
		<Spanish>Pintura Rupestre</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAVE_PAINTING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Cave Paintings[COLOR_REVERT] are paintings on cave walls and ceilings, and the term is used especially for those dating to prehistoric times. The earliest known European cave paintings date to 32,000 years ago. The purpose of the cave paintings is not known. The evidence suggests that they were not merely decorations of living areas, since the caves in which they have been found do not have signs of ongoing habitation. Also, they are often in areas of caves that are not easily accessed. Some theories hold that they may have been a way of transmitting information, while other theories ascribe them a religious or ceremonial purpose.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAVE_PAINTING_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Cave Painting[COLOR_REVERT] to increase your culture output in your cities.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye una [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Pintura Rupestre[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar la cultura en tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<!-- Hunting Instruction -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNTING_INSTRUCTION</Tag>
		<English>Hunting Instruction</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNTING_INSTRUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Hunting[COLOR_REVERT] has an extremely long history and may well pre-date the rise of species Homo sapiens. While our earliest Hominid ancestors were probably frugivore or omnivore, there is evidence that early Homo, and possibly already Australopithecine species have used larger animals for subsistence, and that hunting may have been one of the multiple environmental factors leading to replacement of holocene megafauna by smaller herbivores.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNTING_INSTRUCTION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Hunting Instruction[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the abilities of your [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Hunter[COLOR_REVERT] units.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Hunting Lodge -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNTING_LODGE</Tag>
		<English>Hunting Lodge</English>
		<Spanish>Caba&#241;a del Cazador</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNTING_LODGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Hunting[COLOR_REVERT] has an extremely long history and may well pre-date the rise of species Homo sapiens. While our earliest Hominid ancestors were probably frugivore or omnivore, there is evidence that early Homo, and possibly already Australopithecine species have used larger animals for subsistence, and that hunting may have been one of the multiple environmental factors leading to replacement of holocene megafauna by smaller herbivores.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNTING_LODGE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Hunting Lodge[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the growth of your cities.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye una [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Caba&#241;a del Cazador[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar el crecimiento de tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<!-- Knowledge Inheritance -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KNOWLEDGE_INHERITANCE</Tag>
		<English>Knowledge Inheritance</English>
		<Spanish>Herencia de Conocimiento</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KNOWLEDGE_INHERITANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Knowledge[COLOR_REVERT] is defined variously as (i) expertise, and skills acquired by a person through experience or education; the theoretical or practical understanding of a subject, (ii) what is known in a particular field or in total; facts and information or (iii) awareness or familiarity gained by experience of a fact or situation.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Knowledge acquisition involves complex cognitive processes: perception, learning, communication, association and reasoning. The term knowledge is also used to mean the confident understanding of a subject with the ability to use it for a specific purpose if appropriate.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KNOWLEDGE_INHERITANCE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Knowledge Inheritance[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the science output of your cities.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye una [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Herencia de Tradici&#243;n[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar la raz&#243;n de cambio en ciencia de tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Lascaux Paints -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LASCAUX_PAINTS</Tag>
		<English>Lascaux Paints</English>
		<Spanish>Pinturas de Lascaux</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LASCAUX_PAINTS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lascaux[COLOR_REVERT] is the setting of a complex of caves in southwestern France famous for its prehistoric cave paintings. The original caves are located near the village of Montignac, in the Dordogne département. They contain some of the most well-known Upper Paleolithic art. These paintings are estimated to be 16,000 years old. They primarily consist of realistic images of large animals, most of which are known from fossil evidence to have lived in the area at the time. In 1979, Lascaux was added to the UNESCO World Heritage Sites list along with other prehistoric sites in the Vézère valley.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]The cave was discovered on 12 September 1940 by four teenagers, Marcel Ravidat, Jacques Marsal, Georges Agnel, and Simon Coencas, as well as Ravidat's dog, Robot . Public access was made easier after World War II. By 1955, the carbon dioxide produced by 1,200 visitors per day had visibly damaged the paintings. The cave was closed to the public in 1963 in order to preserve the art. After the cave was closed, the paintings were restored to their original state, and are now monitored on a daily basis. Rooms in the cave include The Great Hall of the Bulls, the Lateral Passage, the Shaft of the Dead Man, the Chamber of Engravings, the Painted Gallery, and the Chamber of Felines.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LASCAUX_PAINTS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Lascaux Paintings[COLOR_REVERT] to have one happy citizen in every city.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye las [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Pinturas de Lascaux[COLOR_REVERT] para tener un ciudadano alegre en cada ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Library -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LIBRARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Libraries[COLOR_REVERT] boost your cities' research and provide culture. They are required to build [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universities[COLOR_REVERT], the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Great Library[COLOR_REVERT] wonder, and the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Epic[COLOR_REVERT] national wonder.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioth&#232;ques[COLOR_REVERT] am&#233;liorent la recherche et produisent de la culture. Elles sont n&#233;cessaires pour construire des [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#233;s[COLOR_REVERT], la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande biblioth&#232;que[COLOR_REVERT], et l'[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epop&#233;e nationale[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotheken[COLOR_REVERT] erh&#246;hen den kulturellen Wert einer Stadt und beschleunigen die Forschung sp&#252;rbar. Dar&#252;ber hinaus sind sie die Voraussetzung f&#252;r den Bau von [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universit&#228;ten[COLOR_REVERT], eines Weltwunders ([COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gro&#223;e Bibliothek[COLOR_REVERT]) und der Nationalen Wunder [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Nationalepos[COLOR_REVERT].</German>
		<Italian>Le [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]biblioteche[COLOR_REVERT] aumentano la ricerca e la cultura delle citt&#224;. Sono necessarie per la realizzazione di [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]universit&#224;[COLOR_REVERT], della Meraviglia [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Grande Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] e delle Meraviglia Nazionali [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poema Patriottico[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Las [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Bibliotecas[COLOR_REVERT] impulsan la investigaci&#243;n de las ciudades y proporcionan cultura. Son necesarias para construir [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Universidades[COLOR_REVERT], la maravilla de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Gran Biblioteca[COLOR_REVERT] y las maravilla nacionales de la [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epopeya nacional[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- National Slave Auction -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION</Tag>
		<English>National Slave Auction</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The national Slave Auction is a centralized slave sale and distribution center that provides an empire with the means to provide cheap labor to all cities of the empire.  Slaves were moved to areas requiring labor which guaranteed that they would never consume resourses without providing a benefit to their owners.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_REVERT] provides a free Slave Market in all of your cities and a +1 happiness bonus in the founding city.  It increases it's city's odds of generating a Great Merchant.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_NATIONAL_SLAVE_AUCTION_PYTHON</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Slave Auction[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT] increases slavery infrastrucre nationwide[COLOR_REVERT]!</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Palisade -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALISADE</Tag>
		<English>Palisade</English>
		<Spanish>Empalizada</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALISADE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Palisade[COLOR_REVERT] is a wooden fence or wall of variable height, used as a defensive structure.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Palisades were an excellent option for small forts or other hastily constructed fortifications. Since they were wood, they could be quickly and easily built from materials readily available. They proved to be effective protection for short-term conflicts, and were an effective deterrent against small forces. However, due to their wooden construction, they were also very vulnerable to fire and siege weapons.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALISADE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Palisade[COLOR_REVERT] to increase a cities defence.</English>
		<Spanish>Construye una [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Empalizada[COLOR_REVERT] para incrementar el bono de defensa en tus ciudades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Skara Brae -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SKARA_BRAE</Tag>
		<English>Skara Brae</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SKARA_BRAE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Skara Brae[COLOR_REVERT] is a large stone-built Neolithic settlement, located on the Bay of Skaill on the west coast of mainland Orkney, Scotland. It consists of ten clustered houses, and was occupied from roughly 3100-2500BC. It is Europe's most complete Neolithic village and the level of preservation is such that it has gained UNESCO World Heritage Site status.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]The outline of several stone buildings was revealed and initial excavations were undertaken by William Watt, the laird of Skaill. It was fully excavated between 1928 and 1930 by Vere Gordon Childe following another storm in 1926. These stone buildings were built out of flagstones that were naturaly eroded by the ocean. Archeologists believe that these structures were once covered by timber roofs that have since eroded. the supply of timber in the area was limited but there was a large supply of the flagstones from the nearby ocean already cut to size by the tides.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Skara Brae's inhabitants were apparently makers and users of grooved ware. The houses used earth sheltering but, being sunk into the ground, they were built into mounds of pre-existing domestic waste (rubbish) known as "middens". Although the midden provided the houses with a small degree of stability, its most important purpose was to act as a layer of insulation against Orkney's harsh winter climate. On average, the houses measure 40 square metres in size with a large square room containing a large hearth which would have been used for heating and cooking. As few trees grow on the island, the people of Skara Brae used driftwood and whalebone, with turf thatch, to roof their dwellings.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SKARA_BRAE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build the [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]Skara Brae[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the time of [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Golden Ages[COLOR_REVERT] for your civilization.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT> <!-- Slave Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET</Tag>
		<English>Slave Market</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Slave Market is the local slave auction block in a city where slaves are displayed prior to sale.  Nearly all ancient civilizations were built on slave labour and slavery existed even in modern times despite attempts to stamp it out.  The slave market was a source of cheap labor and civic pride, as defeated rivals and captured enemies were often displayed for the amusement of the city's citizens prior to begining their labours to build up the very civilizations they opposed.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Slave Market[COLOR_REVERT] provides a 25% production bonus and a +1 happiness bonus in any city it is built in. Allows for the purchase of slaves. Doubles Production for leaders with Organized or Industrius traits.</English>
	</TEXT>

	<TEXT> <!-- Stone Weapons Workshop -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONE_WEAPONS_WORKSHOP</Tag>
		<English>Stone Weapons Workshop</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONE_WEAPONS_WORKSHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The use of stone weapons is not limited to man, but was one of the first stages in mans progression to more advanced tool use that enabled him to survive in hostile climates and live alongside and defeat creatures that are stronger, faster or both than himself.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONE_WEAPONS_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Build a [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stone Weapons Workshop[COLOR_REVERT] to increase the abilities of your Stone Age Military Units.</English>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>